# İsmail Sümer Çetin

Software Engineer

Ankara, Turkey sumercetin3@gmail.com

Github: github.com/ismailsumercetin Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/ismailsumercetin

### ABOUT ME

I am a passionate, detail-oriented Software Engineer with more than 3 years of professional experience, specializing in Frontend Development (Javascript - Typescript - React). I define myself as quick adapter and learner. I am keen on working with various technologies, as it motivates me to enhance the quality of my work. I consider myself to have strong communication skills, and I always prioritize effective communication in a workplace.

### Working Experience

### Frontend Developer (Payments)

Hacettepe Teknokent, Ankara, TR

 $\it Jotform\ Inc.$  -  $\it Full\ featured\ online\ form\ builder\ having\ 20+\ million\ users\ worldwide.$ 

March 2021 - Currently

- Maintenance and bug-fixing of 40+ payment integrations processing millions of dollars each month.
- Developed a right panel for product and gateway management as part of Jotform Store Builder project, which allows users to sell products and collect payments online using another product of Jotform: Jotform App Builder. Currently used by 100k+ users.
- Implemented inline editing in the Jotform Product List form field, enabling users to efficiently add, delete, and update products, resulting in significant time savings during payment form creation.
- Created multiple alternative payment gateway integrations, now serving over 20k users: Venmo, Apple & Google Pay, Cash App Pay.
- Created the 'Donation Box' field in Jotform Form Builder, featuring an innovative configuration panel with enhanced functionalities.
- Enhanced the Product List element by streamlining store actions and API payloads, significantly improving performance and preventing data loss in the end.
- Writing periodical end-to-end (e2e) tests to automate the testing process for all features of the Product List using CucumberJS (Playwright).

### Trainee Frontend Developer

Hacettepe Teknokent, Ankara, TR

 $\it Jot form\ Inc.$  -  $\it Full\ featured\ online\ form\ builder\ having\ 20+\ million\ users\ worldwide.$ 

July 2020 - March 2021

- Worked as Technical Support Specialist for 4 days, and Trainee Frontend Developer for a day in a week.
- Co-piloting and developing small-sized projects using React, vanilla Javascript and various libraries during trainee days.
- Providing workarounds-solutions to issues users encounter, which also allowed me to use and discover different products of Jotform.

### Software Development Intern

Bilkent Cyberpark, Ankara, TR

Feb. 2019 - May 2019

• Worked on various modules of a comprehensive web project (SREDIM) about occupational health and safety management.

Technologies Used: Javascript (AngularJS), Grails, MVC architecture

Website: https://sredim.com/

### EDUCATION

Ekinoks Software

# İhsan Doğramacı Bilkent University

Ankara, TR

Bachelor of Science (BSc) in Computer Technology and Information Systems - 50% Scholarship;

Sep. 2016 - Jun. 2020

- 2015 2016: English Language Preparatory Program, Grade: 116.5/150.
- CGPA: 3.53/4 (Courses available in transcript).

## Waterford Institute of Technology (Erasmus)

Waterford, IE

School of Science and Computing;

Sep. 2018 - Dec. 2018

 $\circ\,$  Studied abroad for one semester (Courses available in transcript).

### Skills & Tools

- Technologies I Frequently Use: Javascript / Typescript, React, Redux, Context API, CSS3 (SASS-SCSS), Tailwind, Styled Components, Git, SQL (MySQL), Jest, Playwright, CucumberJS.
- Have Knowledge: PHP, Laravel, Java, Python, Django, Pandas, C Language, R Language, CI/CD (Jenkins), Webpack, Jest, Flux, OpenGL/GLUT, Kotlin, Swift, Node.js, Express.js, NoSQL (MongoDB), MVC Architecture, Design Patterns.

#### Projects

• A Data-Driven Approach to Study Turkish Macroeconomic Financial Fragilities: A senior year project of 4 people. The project can store and retrieve data provided by TCB(Turkish Central Bank) in a database for access at different granularity. It will be able to retrieve, filter and explore data by visualizing it, to perform some key ratio and index calculations by using balance sheet data and FOF (Flow of Funds) data matrix, to perform scenario, sensitivity and statistical stress testing for financial stability analysis.

Technologies Used: Python (Django, Pandas), HTML, CSS, Javascript (Ajax)

- Filemaker System For a Book Store Freelance: Developed a web application where user can see approximately 6500 books in a dashboard, create and delete books, create and delete tags, assign books to tags, perform all-column search for a specific book from a specific tag or from the whole list, adjust and save field order, create and delete inputs (dropdown, number, multiselect etc.), create and delete template types, and adjust inputs for each template by using drag and drop. Technologies Used: WAMP stack, Javascript, dragula(drag&drop library), jQuery(UI, Ajax) and Bootstrap 4.
- E-Commerce Website CTIS256 Term Project: Developed an e-commerce website with a team of 4. Technologies Used: WAMP stack, Javascript, jQuery, Bootstrap
- Kindly see other open-source projects on my GitHub page.

### LANGUAGES

Turkish: NativeEnglish: FluentSpanish: Beginner

### EVENTS & AWARDS

- Jotform Technical Events
  - Accessibility Week (2023): Made payment product more accessible within Jotform.
  - Fix Week (2021): Query improvements on back end (PHP) using models.
  - Performance Week (2021): Implemented hacky ways to boost performance in various Jotform systems.
  - Hack Week (2020): Implemented a real-time chatbot (MyPodo) whose aim is to help Jotform users with their technical issues.

Technologies Used: Javascript (React), PHP, OpenAI API (GPT3)

- 2020: CTIS System Development Award Ranked Second
  - o Our senior year project "FofViz: A Data-Driven Approach to Study Turkish Macroeconomic Financial Fragilities" came second among 13 projects.
- 2019: Mustafa Akgül Linux Free Software Summer Camp Web Programming with Laravel
  - Developed a social media web application using Laravel Framework in which users can write and share articles, follow each
    other, leave comment to articles and get notifications.
- 2019: Hackinoks Smart Assistant Hackathon
  - Developed a Google Smart Assistant application with a team of 3, where a user tells the eatable materials in their refrigerator, and the assistant recommends random foods that can be prepared with them.
     Technologies Used: Node.js, DialogFlow, PostgreSQL